Guide to the Royal Palm Artifacts and Ephemera Collection 19th-20th century
University of Chicago Library
Royal Palm Artifacts and Ephemera. Collection
2.25 linear feet (2 boxes)
Hanna Holborn Gray Special Collections Research Center University of Chicago Library 1100 East 57th Street Chicago, Illinois 60637 U.S.A.
This collection contains a variety of artifacts and print ephemera. Included are political items from the 20th century, University of Chicago and Hyde Park memorabilia, a small collection of recipes and information on home remedies, and patriotic memorabilia. The cigar box in which this material was found is also included.
Information on Use
Access
The collection is open for research.
Scope Note
This collection contains a variety of artifacts and print ephemera. Included are political material from the 20th century, University of Chicago and Hyde Park memorabilia, a small collection of recipes and information on home remedies, and patriotic items. The cigar box in which this material was found is also included.
Related Resources
The following related resources are located in the Department of Special Collections:
http://www.lib.uchicago.edu/e/spcl/select.html
Artifacts. Collection
Subject Headings
University of Chicago; Formulas, recipes, etc.; Hyde Park (Chicago, Ill.); Traditional medicine; Patriotism -- United States; Politics -- United States
INVENTORY
- University of Chicago, ceremonial ribbons and centennial pin, 20th century (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Hyde Park Hotel pencil and Hotel del Prado postcard, 19th-20th century (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Political ephemera, Workers Party, Dewey-Bricker, Carol Moseley Braun, Franklin Delano Roosevelt, 20th century (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Patriotic ephemera, early 20th century (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Clippings, broadsides and correspondence regarding recipes and home remedies, ca. late 19th-early 20th century (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Lowell Offering, fragment of cover, 1845 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- F.X. Jungwirth, Ansicht von München vom Gasteigberg, reproduction of 1766 print, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Menu, bookmark and Valentine's Day cards, ca. 1930s-1960s (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Royal Palm cigar box, circa 1970s (Box 2)
- University of Chicago, James R. Watkins, signature printing block, 20th century (Box 2)
- University of Chicago, public relations awards medals, 20th century (Box 2)
- University of Chicago, pins, 20th century (Box 2)
- Centennial medals, 1889 (Box 2)
- Political ephemera, Frank O. Lowden, ca. 1920s (Box 2)